+81 70-2024-3012

Objective

Professional writer with over 10 years of experience in the fields of engineering, commercial and technical writing, and education looking to find a position with an organization aligned with the paradigm of doing the most good for the world at large.

Experience

Freelance Copywriter

2018-Present Various Companies, including The Hidden Japan (Japan) and Nativiz (France)

- Based on the client's request, research various subjects in industries ranging from software development to green energy, and write engaging stories appropriate to the audience (lay or technical)
- Provide succinct, SEO-friendly content for various online media outlets
- Meet and strategize with the client over objectives for the writing, whether they be informative, PR, or a call to action on the reader

Other Jobs

2018-Present

- Freelance web developer, front-end focused, self-taught
- English Teacher, Nine Point Nine Eikaiwa (Japan), students of all ages

10+ Years experience with Tosoh Quartz, an international corporation in the semiconductor supply chain industry

Technology Exchange Liaison

1/2017-Present Tosoh Quartz Japan, Yamagata

Acted as intermediary between Japan and US factories for technology exchange relating to semiconductor grade quartzware

Product Engineer

1/2013 -1/2017 Tosoh Quartz, Portland, Oregon

- Wrote and presented monthly technical, evidence-based summaries to our major customer in regard to production change requests, ongoing projects, and quality scorecard
- Managed teams to perform Root Cause / Corrective Action analysis, and provided engineering management with highly recommendations toward further accurate reports and improvements

RPM (Rapid Prototype Materials) Engineer 1/2010 -1/2013 Tosoh Quartz, Portland, Oregon

- Created error-free manufacturing blueprints and technical documents for high level technicians
- Wrote clear, easy to read procedures regarding safety, machine operation, and material handling for entry level operators
- Acted as primary point of contact and technical interface for the customer throughout the build

Training Development Specialist 2/2008 – 1/2010 Tosoh Quartz, Portland, Oregon

Provided in-house production of training videos and other training materials

Education

University of South Florida, Tampa 1998-2002

Bachelor of Science, Industrial and Management Systems Engineering

Skills

Native English fluency, conversational Japanese. Excellent verbal and written skills. Ability to write for different audiences and in different styles. Writing samples available on request.

High attention to detail and a familiarity with various business-oriented continuous improvement methodologies such as lean manufacturing and Six Sigma. Experience with data-driven decision making and team coordination across various departments and business processes.

I have some proficiency with the following technologies (most of which pertain to web development): HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Node, npm, Gulp, Wordpress, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Chrome Developer Tools